kolor.com 2019-06-30

# Terms of Use and Policies

Updated June 18, 2019 

At Lifewire, we take online privacy seriously and we respect the concerns of our community of users. In this policy (the “Privacy Policy”) we describe our privacy practices with regard to information we collect through Lifewire.com and its affiliated sites (collectively, the “Site”), to help you make informed decisions about how you share information when you visit or use the site, as well as your rights in determining what we do with the information that we collect or hold about you. 

### Understanding How Information Is Collected on Lifewire:

#### Information You May Choose to Provide to Us

We may collect information, including personal data, directly from you if you choose to provide that information. For example, you may provide us with your name and contact information (such as an email address), date of birth, or other details of that nature, when you sign up for our newsletters or participate in promotions or surveys on the Site. 

You also may choose to provide personal data about yourself when you participate in forums or discussions on the Site. Please be aware that information you post in these forums may be viewed or captured by anyone who visits the Site, therefore you should avoid posting sensitive personal data that you would not want to be available to the public. 

#### Information That Is Automatically Collected When You Visit Lifewire

When you access the Site, we and our third-party partners may automatically collect certain information about your visit using tools such as cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies. The information collected automatically when you visit the Site may include your IP address, characteristics of your operating system, information about your browser and system settings, data about the computer or mobile device you use to access the Site, unique device identifiers, clickstream data (which shows the page-by-page path you take as you browse the Site). We or our third-party partners may combine information that each of us collects automatically with other information about you, including information you choose to provide. 

**Cookies** are small files that websites and other online services use to store information about users on the users’ own computers. This Site may use cookies (such as HTTP and HTML5 cookies and Flash cookies), as well as other types of local storage. For more information about cookies, you may visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). See the section below regarding Your choices to learn more about how you may limit or disable cookies on your computer. If you choose to disable cookies, that could affect certain features of the Site that use cookies to enhance their functionality. 

To manage our automatic data collection, we may place tags (often referred to as “web beacons”) on pages on the Site or in emails we send to you. **Web beacons** are small files that link web pages to particular web servers and their cookies, and they may be used for a variety of purposes, such as counting the number of visitors to the Site, analyzing how users navigate around the Site, assessing how many emails that we send are actually opened and which articles or links are viewed by visitors. 

We also use third-party web analytics services, such as Google Analytics, on the Site, to provide us with statistics and other information about visitors to the Site. 

**“Do Not Track” Signals.** Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “do not track” signal to websites and online services you visit. At this time there is no consensus among industry participants as to the meaning of “do not track” in this context. Like many other websites, Lifewire.com is not configured to respond to “do not track” signals from browsers. [Click here to learn more about "do not track" signals.](https://allaboutdnt.com/)

Finally, companies that provide certain third-party apps, tools, widgets, and plug-ins that may appear on the Site (for example, Facebook “Like” buttons), also may use automated means to collect information regarding your interactions with these features. This information collection is subject to the privacy policies or notices of those providers. 

Further information regarding our use of cookies and other tracking technologies is described in our Cookies Disclosure. 

#### How We May Use Information We Collect

We may use the information gathered on Lifewire for various purposes, including the purposes listed below. For example, if you were to contact us with a question and provide your email address, we would use the email address you provided to respond to your inquiry. In addition, we use information we collect from you and through the Site to: 

  * Provide products and services you request (such as when you sign up to receive our email newsletters); 
  * Respond to requests, questions, and comments, and provide other types of user support; 
  * Offer you products and services via marketing communications, or direct you to portions of this Site or other websites, that we believe may interest you; 
  * To serve advertising, content and offers to you based on your interests and online activities, from us or third parties; 
  * Communicate about, and administer your participation in, events, programs, contests, and other offers or promotions; 
  * Carry out, evaluate, and improve our business (which may include developing new features for the Site; analyzing and enhancing the user experience on the Site; assessing the effectiveness of our marketing and advertising; and managing our communications); 
  * Perform data analytics regarding usage of the Site (including market and customer research, trend analysis, financial analysis, and anonymization of personal data); 
  * Guard against, identify, and prevent fraud and other criminal activity, claims, and other liabilities; and 
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements, law enforcement requests, and our company policies. 

#### How We May Share Information

Our agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers may have access to information we collect through the Site to carry out work on our behalf. Those parties are subject to confidentiality obligations and are restricted from using personal data collected through the Site for purposes other than to provide the requested assistance. In addition, we may share information: 

  * With our affiliates for internal business purposes; 
  * If we are required to do so by law, regulation, or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena); 
  * In response to requests from government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities, including to meet national security requirements; 
  * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; 
  * With respect to analytics and statistical information, to inform advertisers about the nature of our user base; 
  * In the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including a reorganization, dissolution, or liquidation). In such an event, we will seek to provide you with commercially reasonable notice, e.g., via email and/or notice on our website, of any change in ownership, incompatible new uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information; and 
  * With your consent or at your discretion. 

#### Data Retention and Access

We will retain your personal data only for as long as necessary for the purposes it was retained, such as to enable you to use the Website and your products or to provide services to you. In some instances, we may retain data for longer periods in order to comply with applicable laws (including those regarding document retention), resolve disputes with any parties, and otherwise as necessary to allow us to conduct our business. All personal data we retain will be subject to this Privacy Policy and our internal retention guidelines. 

We respect your control over your information and, upon request, we will seek to confirm your identity and whether we hold or are processing information that we have collected from you. You also have the right to amend or update inaccurate or incomplete personal information, request deletion of your personal information, or request that we no longer use it. Under certain circumstances we will not be able to fulfill your request, such as if it interferes with our regulatory obligations, affects legal matters, we cannot verify your identity, or it involves disproportionate cost or effort, but in any event we will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe and provide you an explanation. In order to make such a request of us, please email us at [privacy@lifewire.com](mailto:privacy@lifewire.com)

#### Your Choices

**Unsubscribe from emails.** To unsubscribe from a particular newsletter, click the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of that email newsletter. If you would like to globally opt-out from all Lifewire email campaigns, please send an email to [optout@lifewire.com](mailto:optout@lifewire.com) with "Unsubscribe" in the subject line. When we send newsletters to subscribers we may allow advertisers or partners to include messages in those newsletters, or we may send dedicated newsletters on behalf of those advertisers or partners. We may disclose your opt-out choices to third parties so that they can honor your preferences in accordance with applicable laws. 

**Blocking cookies.** Certain browsers may be configured to notify you when you receive cookies, or allow you to restrict or disable certain cookies. If you choose to disable cookies, however, that could affect certain features of the Site that use cookies to enhance their functionality. 

**Disabling local shared objects (“Flash cookies”).** We may use other kinds of local storage that function similarly, but are stored in different parts of your computer from ordinary browser cookies. Your browser may allow you to disable its HTML5 local storage or delete information contained in its HTML5 local storage. [Click here](http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html) for details about deleting information contained in "local shared objects" or adjusting related preferences. 

**Options concerning third-party ad networks.** As described in this Privacy Policy, we and third parties may use cookies and similar tracking technologies to collect information and infer your interests for interest-based advertising purposes. If you would prefer to not receive personalized ads based on your browser or device usage, you may generally opt out of interest-based advertising by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note that you will continue to see advertisements, but such advertisements will no longer be tailored to your interests. For more information about third-party ad networks and services that use these technologies, you can visit [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) and [click here](http://aboutads.info/choices) to opt out or to learn more about your options. You also may visit the [NAI's site for additional options](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) on how to opt out of interest-based advertising. 

#### How We Protect Personal Data

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal data you provide against accidental, unlawful, or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure, or use. That said, it is not possible to guarantee the security of information transmitted online, and you assume some risk with regard to the security of information you provide through any website, including this Site. If you have a data security inquiry, you may contact us by emailing [security@lifewire.com](mailto:security@lifewire.com). To request an invite to our bug bounty program to submit reports on vulnerabilities found on Lifewire.com, you may contact us by emailing [bugbounty@lifewire.com](mailto:bugbounty@lifewire.com). 

#### Links From Lifewire to Other Websites

On this Site we may provide links to other websites that are controlled by third parties. Linked websites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review. We are not responsible for the content, usage terms, or privacy policies of websites that we do not own or control. 

#### Surveys and Quizzes

While you are visiting Lifewire, you may have the opportunity to participate in surveys, quizzes, or other interactive features that request information about you and your opinions and preferences. Your participation in these features is entirely voluntary. If you do choose to participate, please be aware that these features may be operated by a third party that is not controlled by Lifewire, and therefore the information you provide may be collected by the third party and subject to its privacy policy. 

#### Children’s Privacy

This Site is not designed or intended for use by children, and we do not knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of 16. If we become aware that we have collected personal data from a child under the age of 16, we will delete any such information. 

#### Information for Users Outside the United States

Your personal data may be stored, transferred and processed in and to the United States and in other countries by our affiliates and/or service providers. The data protection laws in these countries may provide a lower standard of protection for your personal data than your country of residence. We take great care in protecting your personal data and have put in place adequate mechanisms to protect it when it is transferred internationally. We will transfer your personal data in compliance with applicable data protection laws and will implement suitable safeguards to ensure that your personal data is adequately secured by any third party that will access your information (for instance, by using the Model Clauses as approved by the European Commission). 

By using our Site and providing personal data to us, you consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the collection, use, maintenance, transfer to and processing of your personal data in the United States or other countries or territories, and, unless otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, we use this consent as the legal basis for that data transfer. 

If you have questions or wish to obtain more information about the international transfer of your personal data or the implemented safeguards, please send us an email to [privacy@lifewire.com](mailto:privacy@lifewire.com). 

#### How We’ll Inform You About Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may update this online privacy policy periodically to reflect changes to our privacy practices, such as how we collect or use personal data. If we propose to make any material changes, we will post a prominent notice on the lifewire.com home page to notify you of significant changes to this policy, and we indicate at the top of the policy the date when it was most recently updated. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. 

#### How to Contact Us

If you have questions about this policy or about our privacy practices, you may contact us by emailing [privacy@lifewire.com](mailto:privacy@lifewire.com). 

If you are a California resident inquiring about your California privacy rights, please include “California privacy rights request” in the subject line of your email. 

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area inquiring about your rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), please include “GDPR privacy rights request” in the subject line of your email. 

You may also write to: 

1500 Broadway, 6th Floor   
New York, NY 10036 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

### Jurisdiction Specific Provisions

#### Our Notice to California Residents

Subject to certain limits, under California law California residents may ask us to provide them with a list of the categories of personal data that we have disclosed to third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, as well as the identity of those third parties. California residents may contact us as specified in the How to Contact Us section below to make a request for this information. 

#### If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA):

  1. #### Controller of your Personal Data

The controller of your personal data under this Privacy Policy is About, Inc., with an address of 1500 Broadway, 6th Floor, New York, NY 10036. Our local representative with respect to the GDPR can be contacted at [privacy@lifewire.com](mailto:privacy@lifewire.com). 

  2. #### Legal Bases for Using Personal Data

We process your personal data only if we have a legal basis to do so, including: 

    1. to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations;
    2. for the performance of our contract with you or to take steps at your request before entering into a contract;
    3. for our legitimate interests or those of a third party;
    4. where you have given consent to our specific use.

The purpose for which we use and process your information and the legal basis on which we carry out each type of processing is further explained below. 

Purposes for which we will process the information

| 

Legal Basis for the processing  
  
---|---  
  
To provide products and services you request.

| 

It is necessary for us to process your personal data in order to deliver the services and process transactions according to the applicable contract between us.  
  
To respond to requests, questions, and comments, and provide other types of user support.

| 

It is necessary for us to respond to requests, questions, and comments, and provide other types of user support in order to take steps at your request or according to the applicable contract between us.  
  
To offer you products and services in marketing communications, or direct you to portions of this Site or other websites, that we believe may interest you.

| 

We may send electronic marketing communications to you if you have consented to these communications.  It is in our legitimate interest to market products and services to you by other means and to direct you to portions of this Site or other websites that we believe may interest you. We consider this use to be proportionate and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.  
  
To communicate about, and administer your participation in, events, programs, contests, and other offers or promotions

| 

We will send electronic communications to you if you have consented to these communications. With respect to other communications, it is in our legitimate interest to communicate to you and administer your participation in, our events, programs, contests, and other offers or promotions. We consider this use to be proportionate and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.  
  
To carry out, evaluate, and improve our business (which may include developing new features for the Site; analyzing and enhancing the user experience on the Site; assessing the effectiveness of our marketing and advertising; and managing our communications.

| 

It is in our legitimate interests to process your personal data to carry out these activities. We consider this use to be proportionate and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.  
  
To perform data analytics regarding usage of the Site (including market and customer research, trend analysis, financial analysis, and anonymization of personal data).

| 

It is in our legitimate interests to process your personal data to carry out these activities. We consider this use to be proportionate and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.  
  
To serve advertising, content and offers to you based on your interests and online activities, from us or third parties.

| 

We will serve you advertising, content and offers to you based on your interests and online activities if you have consented to this processing.  
  
To enable our affiliates or service providers to perform certain activities on our behalf;

| 

It is necessary for us to process your personal data in this manner in order to deliver the services and process transactions according to the applicable contract between us. It is also in our legitimate interest to enable our service providers and affiliates to perform certain activities on our behalf. We consider this use to be proportionate and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.  
  
To notify you of any changes to the Site that may affect you.

| 

It is necessary for us to process your personal data in order to deliver the services and process transactions according to the applicable contract between us.  
  
    * If we are required to do so by law, regulation, or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena); 
    * In response to requests from government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities, including to meet national security requirements; 
    * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; and 
    * In the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including a reorganization, dissolution, or liquidation). In such an event, we will seek to provide you with commercially reasonable notice, e.g., via email and/or notice on our website, of any change in ownership, incompatible new uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information; and 
| 

We conduct this processing to comply with our legal obligations and to protect the public interest.  
  
    * Guard against, identify, and prevent fraud and other criminal activity, claims, and other liabilities; and 
    * Comply with applicable legal requirements, law enforcement requests, and our company policies. 
| 

We conduct this processing to comply with our legal obligations and to protect the public interest.  
  
  3. #### International Transfers

Some of our processing of your data will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). Some of our external third-party service providers are also based outside of the EEA, and their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA. This includes the United States. Where personal data is transferred to and stored in a country not determined by the European Commission as providing adequate levels of protection for personal data, we take steps to provide appropriate safeguards to protect your personal data, including when appropriate entering into standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission, obliging recipients to protect your personal data. 

  4. #### Retention of Personal Data

We will retain your personal data only for as long as necessary for the purposes it was retained, such as to enable you to use the Site and your products or to provide services to you. In some instances, we may retain data for longer periods in order to comply with applicable laws (including those regarding document retention), resolve disputes with any parties, and otherwise as necessary to allow us to conduct our business. All personal data we retain will be subject to this Privacy Policy and our internal retention guidelines. 

  5. #### Data Subject Access Rights

You have the following rights: 

    * Right of access to your personal data: You have the right to ask us for confirmation on whether we are processing your personal data, and access to the personal data and related information. 
    * Right to correction: You have the right to have your personal data corrected, as permitted by law. 
    * Right to erasure: You have the right to ask us to delete your personal data, as permitted by law. 
    * Right to withdraw consent: You have the right to withdraw consent that you have provided. 
    * Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority: You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in the member state of your habitual residence. 
    * Right to restriction of processing: You have the right to request the limiting of our processing under limited circumstances. 
    * Right to data portability: You have the right to receive the personal data that you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and you have the right to transmit that information to another controller, including to have it transmitted directly, where technically feasible. 
    * Right to object: You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data, as permitted by law, under limited circumstances. 

In order to exercise any of these rights, please contact us according to the “How to Contact Us” section herein. Please note that the above rights are not absolute and we may be entitled to refuse requests, wholly or partly, where exceptions under the applicable law apply. 

### Lifewire Cookie Disclosure

Provider | Name of Cookie | Purpose | Type | Duration  
---|---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics  |  _ga  |  Used to distinguish users.  |  Persistent  |  2 years   
Google Analytics  |  _gid  |  Used to distinguish users.  |  Persistent  |  24 Hours   
Google Analytics  |  _gat_<property-id> |  Used to throttle request rate.  |  Persistent  |  1 Minute   
Dotdash  |  TMog  |  Dotdash client id - Used to identify unique browsers  |  Persistent  |  68 Years   
Dotdash  |  Mint  |  Dotdash session id - Used to identify all activity within a session  |  Persistent  |  30 Minutes   
Dotdash  |  pc  |  pagecount  |  Persistent  |  30 Minutes   
Dotdash  |  ds_ab  |  AB Testing segmentation information  |  Session  |    
Google (GTM/GA)  |  _dc_gtm_<property-id> |  Used to throttle request rate.  |  Persistent  |  1 Minute   
SailThru  |  sailthru_pageviews  |  Page view count by user on site  |  Persistent  |  30 Minutes   
SailThru  |  sailthru_content  |  Tracks recent pageviews for visitor  |  Persistent  |  1 Hour   
SailThru  |  sailthru_visitor  |  Client Id  |  Persistent  |  1 Hour   
Google DFP  |  __gads  |  Ad targeting  |  Persistent  |  2 Years   
Google  |  gsScrollPos-<num> |  Scroll position tracking  |  Session  |    
Bounce Exchange  |  bounceClientVisit<num>v  |  Client tracking information  |  Persistent  |  30 Minutes   
Google  |  AMP_TOKEN  |  Contains a token that can be used to retrieve a Client ID from AMP Client ID service. Other possible values indicate opt-out, inflight request or an error retrieving a Client ID from AMP Client ID service.  |  Persistent  |  1 Hour   
Quantcast  |  __qca  |  Collects anonymous data on the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded with the purpose of generating reports for optimising the website content.  |  Persistent  |  13 Months
